Jimmy Jones

jimmy.jones@tutanota.com (828) 407-3415

Summary

Detail oriented individual with over 25 years of experience creating aesthetically pleasing, easy to use and engaging user experiences for the web and desktop in a multitude of different technologies. Over 15 years experience working remotely.

Experience

User Experience Consultant - UXFX.io

May 2022 - Present

Working on streamlining the design system process utilizing design tokens and various tools and automated processes to create a more efficient and easier to manage workflow for companies with multiple brands in their portfolios. Focused on integrating design tokens with Figma components and exploring the best way to transform those design tokens into assets to be consumed by component libraries. Exploring ways to document design systems and design tokens to allow consumers, both designers and developers, to easily reason about what the design system provides and how to properly utilize it.

Also working on creating an AI assistant using large language models with vector data stores to provide context and long term memory. The initial goal is to create an assistant that will increase my productivity to the point where the time to spin up and complete new applications is drastically reduced.

Personal Goal Pursuit

April 2021 - Present

Spent time studying state and federal law, state and federal Constitutions, court rules, and used the knowledge to successfully defeat charges brought against me in absence of probable cause by the Archuleta Sheriff's Office and District Attorney for the Colorado 6th Judicial District. Filed multiple federal civil suits under U.S.C. Title 42 § 1983 for conspiracy against rights and deprivation of rights under color of law by public servants.

Personal Projects

May 2019 - Present

Utilized Angular, React, Svelte, Node.js, GraphQL, and Hasura in a variety of personal projects. Full stack dev, including development of auth server using javascript and express, persistence api utilizing Hasura, which exposes a graphql api on top of a Postgres database, and web clients using React, switching to Angular, and ultimately using Svelte.

Senior UX Developer at M8 Systems - (contract position)

March 2021 - April 2021

Utilized Svelte to create a proof of concept progressive web app which was used to help secure first round of capital for startup. Took Figma design comps and created HTML and CSS layouts, then integrated those layouts into a Svelte application.

Independent Business Owner

May 2010 - 2020

Provide expertise and training in user interface design, interaction design and integration for web and desktop across many different technologies.

Senior UX Integrator at XLR8 Software – (Consulting with MarketAxess)

May 2018 – May 2019

Provided UX guidance on new features, suggested and implemented XAML changes to existing WPF client to increase performance and improve User Experience, helped out with changes and additions to C# code base. Also made POC for a web based version of their software using Angular and utilizing Storybook to view existing React component structure.

WPF Integration / Silverlight Integration / Visual Design Consultant at Veracity Solutions September 2009 - 2018

Provided consulting services for various clients related to Windows Presentation Foundation, XAML, Silverlight, WinForms, and visual user interface design.

UX Design, UI Design, WPF / Silverlight Integration, WPF Interactive Designer at IdentityMine May 2006 - April 2008

My duties were mainly on the design side of things with light integration of those designs into XAML. The last year of my time was spent in the WPF Integration side of things, bridging the gap between the designer and the developer.

Contract Web Designer / Developer at Sequoyah Technologies

December 2005 - May 2006

Worked on a variety of projects while at this position, including the design and build out of website templates for a content management system, a flash presentation for a building monitoring service company, and the design and build out of several small websites.

Contract Designer at IdentityMine

May 2005 - November 2005

Worked for IDM in a contract position on a variety of projects, including user interface design and XAML development of WPF demos, website design and development, Flash presentation design and development (ActionScript), graphic asset creation (hi res icons) and smart device conceptual user interface design.

Web and Graphic Designer at Efficiency Technologies

2004 - 2005

Took designers comps and integrated them with a Cold Fusion website that monitored the efficiency of chiller systems in large buildings. Did some cold fusion programming for things like list sorting and paging and passing data back and forth between the web app and MySql database.

Learned a bit of Java and helped write a boiler efficiency web application similar to the chiller efficiency monitoring software that already existed.

Created Flash training which consisted of recording and editing sound tracks, taking graphic assets and consuming them in a Flash app that utilized ActionScript to create training movies for our software.

Web and Graphic Designer at Sequoyah Technologies

2000 - 2004

Involved in graphic design, print design and interaction design. Took graphic designs and turned those into working front ends on a variety of websites using HTML, CSS and some JavaScript, as well as XML, XSLT, PHP, and ASP.net, Flash and Actionscript.

Web Designer at BMC Advertising

1999 - 2000

Involved in graphic design, print design and interaction design. Took graphic designs and turned those into working front ends on a variety of websites using HTML, CSS and some JavaScript.

Graphic Designer

1997 - 1998

Print / Web Designer. Designed and built my first website using Photoshop, Dreamweaver and Notepad.

Education

Oral Roberts University

Commercial Art, 1996 - 1997